>> 演讲者 1: 好奇 " JSDoc " 或 " JSDoc " 之类的角色
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: Curious what the role
of something like JSDoc or
其他表示法标准。
other notation standards are.
听起来好像是机器写代码的问题
It kinda sounds like there's the issue
of writing code for the machine and
然后写密码给那些要在路上读几个星期的人
then writing code for the humans who
have to read it weeks down the road.
我对使用明确的胁迫的说法很有意见
And I'm very persuaded by the arguments
about using explicit coercion,
但在其他情况下，您遇到或
but are there other cases
where you have encountered or
会推荐类似的战术吗
would recommend ancillary
tactics like that?
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 嗯，我当然认为，如果你仔细想想编码，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Well, I certainly think
if you think about coding on the whole,
顺便说下这是个大问题
it's a great question, by the way.
如果你想以完整的方式来表达我的想法
If you think about coding on the whole
as a way to communicate my ideas,
然后有很多方法来交流想法。
then there are lots of
ways to communicate ideas.
其中一个方法是在您编写的代码中，其中一个方法在辅助操作中。
One of the ways is in the code that you
write, one of the ways is in the ancillary
您提到的内容，例如，代码注释。
stuff that you mentioned,
like for example code comments.
现在有人告诉你，你不该有代码评论，
Now some people tell you,
nah you should never need code comments,
代码应该自我解释。
code should explain itself.
您不应更依赖代码注释而不是代码注释。
You should not have more reliance
upon code comments than the code.
我看到的是这样的代码库，就是这样。
And I've seen code bases that
are like that, that are so
在没有代码注释的情况下无法将其计算出来。
inscrutable that without the code comment,
nobody's figuring it out.
但是，代码注释不是要避免的坏事。
But code comments are not
a bad thing to be avoided.
他们没有暴露计划的弱点
They're not exposing some
weakness of the program.
这是代码注释的问题。
Here's the problem with code comments.
人们写他们的代码评论我很抱歉
People write the what in their
code comment, I'm sorry,
他们会写代码注释的方式
they write the how in their code comment.
就像你有一条线说， i++ ，
Like you have a line that says, i++, and
然后你说点增量 i 就是代码注释。
then you say something like
increment i is the code comment.
我知道是递增 i 我能看出来
I know it's incrementing i,
I can see that.
这就是我想让密码告诉我的原因
Here's what I want the code
comment to tell me, why.
为什么需要递增，以及为什么只有 1，为什么不需要 2 或 12?
Why do you need to increment, and
why only by 1, why not by 2 or 12?
告诉我为什么有时告诉我怎么做
Tell me why, and
sometimes maybe tell me how.
但是别告诉我密码是什么
But don't tell me what,
that's what the code's for.
因此，您可以很好地与代码进行沟通。
So yes,
you can communicate well with your code.
如果您在此功能上做了 JS 文档，那么这两个参数也会接收到
If you did a JS doc on this function and
said, these two parameters receive either
你对每个人都很清楚
strings or numbers, then you're very
clearly signaling to everybody,
都知道可能发生了某种胁迫
be aware that some coercion may happen.
但这只是字符串和数字之间的关系，所以我们知道
But it's only between strings and
numbers, and so we know we
缩小了我们所需要关注的角落案件的范围
have narrowed down the scope of corner
cases that we need to be concerned about.
当然，代码注释很有用，我不会完全依赖它们。
Absolutely, code comments can be useful,
I wouldn't rely entirely on them.
我认为在我们的代码中有很多事情是显而易见的。
I think there's lots of things we
can do in our code to be obvious.